realbuzz.com 2018-12-09

# Privacy Policy | realbuzz.com

**Privacy Policy**

**This policy was last updated 11-09-2018**

Thank you for visiting realbuzz.com (the “Website”) and/or _myrealbuzz_ (the “app’’). Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy, we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used by the Website.

For the purpose of the General Data Protection Regulation 2018 (the **Regulation** ), the data controller is The Realbuzz Group Ltd of 4b One City Place, Chester, Cheshire, CH1 3BQ, United Kingdom.

If you have any questions or requests surrounding how we process your personal data, please [complete this form](https://therealbuzzgroup.atlassian.net/servicedesk/customer/portal/24/create/342) and we will respond accordingly.

**Terms of Use**

Your use of the Website and/or app is subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) and the Website and/or app’s Terms of Use, so please read this Privacy Policy and the Website’s Terms of Use before using the Website and/or app. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into, and part of, the Terms of Use (the “Terms of Use”), which governs your use of this Website and/or app in general.  By visiting the Website and/or app you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

**realbuzz.com and myrealbuzz app Terms of use   **

**Personal information**

As the protection of your privacy is of the greatest importance to us, we have created this Privacy policy to communicate our practices regarding the collection and dissemination of ‘personal information’ that can be linked to a specific individual, such as a name, address, gender, phone number, email address, or any other information provided to us by users who have registered with us (“Members”) and email subscribers. You do not have to share personal information to use the Website and/or app. The Website and its associated app does not collect personal information about people without their permission. This Privacy Policy does not apply to entities that we do not own or control, such as third party advertisers, sponsors, licensors, licensees, and service providers. We are not responsible for the information practices of any of these or other third party sites, advertisements or links that may appear on our Website.

Members of the site provide us with the following personal information:

Email address

Display username

Country of residence

Date of birth

Members of the site can provide optional additional personal information in the Profile section of the site including first and last name, telephone number, gender, address, and biometric data including height and weight. This information is optional, but is required for some areas of the site to function.

**How we collate and use personal information**

The Website and/or app gathers personal information by means of the following methods:

When you sign up to the Website and/or app; When you attend events and exhibitions. You may also give us personal information when you correspond with us by phone, email or otherwise. When you access the Website and/or app, we also automatically receive your computer’s internet protocol (IP) address in order to provide us with information that helps us learn about your browser and operating system.

To protect your personal information, we take reasonable precautions and follow industry best practices to make sure it is not inappropriately lost, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

Your personally identifiable information is stored within a secure environment. Personally identifiable information will be gathered and stored in the SAB (Shared Authentication Backend) during your first registration to a SAB associated website/event.

Any subsequent registrations with websites or event organisers who have also registered with us, the SAB will access your personally identifiable information.

In doing so this will access the SAB, which will then populate/pre-fill the registration forms for the associated website/ a particular event organiser.

Consequently, the only personally identifiable information, which is transferred to any associated website/race organiser, is information authorised by you for that particular associated website/event organiser after a process of authentication and authorisation.

This means your personal data may be transferred and stored in multiple geographical locations. By agreeing to the terms of this Privacy Policy you consent to the transfer of your personal data to such countries.

We will only send you email newsletters if you have given us your direct consent or if we have identified a legitimate interest in doing so. We will always balance your own interests and any impact on you when processing your data for the purpose of sending email newsletters. You may immediately unsubscribe from email newsletters at any time by following the process outlined below. In order to provide you with improved, relevant content, we compile information about email response and website usage. This information helps us to better understand our Members' and email subscribers’ site usage patterns and also what types of content and information may help improve your user experience on the Website.

To improve our online services the Website and/or app periodically performs statistical analyses of aggregate user behaviour and characteristics in order to measure interest in and use of various areas of the website and to use such information to improve on the ability to serve you better.

The personal information we gather from subscribers to our email newsletters (including email addresses) is not shared with other organisations or third parties without permission. The Website and/or app is extremely protective of the information gathered through its online membership and email subscriptions. Provided you have given your consent, we may from time to time i) send out emails on behalf of like-minded organisations, but we do not provide them with access to any other personal information, or ii) share your data with other carefully selected organizations for the purposes of contacting you about products and services that we think we may be of interest to you.

Below is an outline of ways which we process your data and our lawful basis for doing so.

**Purpose/Activity**

| 

**Type of data**

| 

**Lawful basis for processing including legitimate interest to do so**  
  
---|---|---  
  
To set up your account on the website

| 

Identity

Contact

| 

Consent

Legitimate interest  
  
To provide website functionality and user tools

| 

Identity

Contact

Technical

| 

Consent

Legitimate interest  
  
To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, data handling and reporting)

| 

Identity

Contact

Usage

Professional

| 

Our legitimate interests to run our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud or prevent access to the data we hold

Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and to measure or understand the effectiveness of  the advertising we serve to you

| 

Identity

Contact

Usage

Marketing and Communications

Technical

| 

Consent

Our legitimate interests to run our business, keep our website and marketing relevant and updated, develop our business and inform our marketing strategy  
  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about services/ products that may be of interest to you

| 

Identity

Contact

Technical

Usage

| 

Consent

Our legitimate interest to develop and grow our business  
  
To send you marketing communications (email newsletters)

| 

Marketing and Communications

Contact

Identity

| 

Consent

Legitimate interest  
  
To notify you of website activity as per your user profile settings

| 

Contact

Identity

| 

Legitimate interest  
  
**Our purpose for holding your personal information**

Our lawful basis for holding your information is that you have provided consent to process your personal data for the purposes of provided site functionality.

You may withdraw consent for processing of your data at any time.

**How long we keep your personal information**

We will continue to process your personal data to provide website services until you withdraw your consent for us to do so, which you can do at any time.

**How we protect your personal information**

The Website and/or app has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of the information under our control. Our web server is located in a locked, secure environment.

We have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and help prevent unauthorised access, maintain data security, and correctly use the information we collect online. To protect your privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to help verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

**Security of the Website and its associated app**

We use the latest security technology to protect your personal information. When you enter your personal details in the checkout pages of realbuzz.com you are in a secure website. Most browsers display a small padlock symbol on your browser to reassure you this is secure. It is your responsibility and not that of the Website to ensure your browser is up-to-date and has the relevant security patches. Most web browsers will display a message too stating that you are entering into a secure website. If at any time you leave the secure area of the Website, your web browser may remind you that you are leaving a secure part of the Website. You will be asked if you want to cancel this reminder for future occasions.  No security measures are perfect or impenetrable. Due to the inherent nature of the Internet as an open global communications vehicle, we cannot guarantee that information, during transmission through the Internet or while stored on our system or otherwise in our care, will be absolutely safe from intrusion by others, such as hackers.

**Collection of personal information by third-party sites and sponsors**

Where we provide links to third party websites (whether or not they are affiliated with the Website and/or app and even if the Website and/or app branding appears on these sites), such websites are not controlled by us and are not covered by this Privacy policy. These links are provided for your convenience only. If you access these sites by using the links provided, the operators of these sites may collect information from you which will be used by them in accordance with their privacy policy. Although where possible we endeavour to ensure that the site operators abide by our Privacy policy, we cannot guarantee that they will and you are advised to check the privacy policy of such third parties before providing information to them.

**The use of cookies**

To enhance your experience of the Website, all of our web pages use "cookies." Cookies are text files we place in your computer's browser to store your preferences. Cookies, by themselves, do not tell us your email address or other personally identifiable information. However, once you choose to furnish the site with personally identifiable information, this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie.

We use cookies to understand site usage and to improve the content and offerings on our sites. For example, we may use cookies to personalise your experience of the Website (e.g. to recognise you by name when you return to the Website), save your password in password-protected areas, and enable you to use shopping carts. We also may use cookies to offer you products of potential interest in emails. If you do not wish to receive cookies, or want to be notified of when they are placed, your browser may permit you to do so. However, this will inhibit the functionality of the Website on your browser.

We use the following cookies:

**Strictly necessary cookies,** These are cookies that are required for the operation of our website. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our website, use a shopping cart or make use of e-billing services.

**Analytical/performance cookies.** They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our website when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.

**Functionality cookies.** These are used to recognise you when you return to our website. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).

**Targeting cookies.** These cookies record your visit to our website, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make our website and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.

**Email and email newsletter communications**

By default all site members will receive standard website and/or app activity/account notifications. All members can choose which standard website and/or app activity/account notifications they wish to receive within the Settings section of their account. In addition to this we will not contact you via email for any purpose except in the following circumstances; you are subscribed to the regular newsletters, you are in breach of the Website and/or app’s Terms of use, maintaining our subscription and unsubscription lists, communicating with you in the event of a change in the ownership of the Website and/or app or its business, or notifying you of our special offers or changes to the Website and/or app, business practices, Terms of use or Privacy policy, unless (i) we are required to do so by applicable law or pursuant to a court or similar order; (ii) as deemed necessary, in the Website’s discretion, to protect the legal rights or the property of the website, a member or third party, or to prevent personal injury; or (iii) you have provided your consent for us to do so.

**How you receive email newsletters from the Website**

You will only receive email newsletters from the Website in the following circumstances: you are a subscriber to the newsletter and/or Website and its associated app or one of our associate sites (unless you have unsubscribed), and/or you signed up to receive newsletters via one of our competitions or at an event or exhibition (unless you have unsubscribed). We use MailChimp as our marketing automation platform, and your data will be processed in accordance with their [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) and [Terms](https://mailchimp.com/legal/terms/).

**How we track HTML newsletters**

The Website makes use of both "open-tracking" and "click-tracking" in our HTML newsletters (i.e. emails that contain text and images). Open-tracking allows us to find out how many people have viewed our email newsletters and click-tracking allows us to find out which links in the newsletter were clicked on. This helps us to refine and improve the editorial content of the Website’s newsletters, and to provide you with relevant information. We may also use predicted demographic data to show specific content to targeted audiences in our HTML newsletters. If you would prefer to opt out of this you may do so by contacting us directly.

**How to unsubscribe from mailing lists**

All Website and/or app communication, whether via email newsletter subscription, and site notifications, provides information on how to unsubscribe quickly and easily. All emails sent out contain a link to unsubscribe. You may update, subscribe or unsubscribe to any newsletter or email communication at any time.

To opt out of receiving communications from the Website please click the 'unsubscribe' link at the bottom of the email newsletter. This link enables you to either update your email subscription or to unsubscribe from all email subscriptions.

**Third-party advertisers**

The Website and/or app allows other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to serve advertisements within the Website and/or app. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and links that appear on the Website and/or app. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalise the advertising content you see.

The Website and/or app does not provide any personally identifiable information to these third-party ad servers or ad networks without your consent or except as part of a specific programme or feature for which you will have the ability to opt in or opt out. However, please note that if an advertiser asks the Website and/or app to show an advertisement to a certain audience (for example, men aged 18-34) or audience segment (for example, men aged 18-24 who have viewed certain channels of content) and you respond to that advertisement, the advertiser or ad server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience they are trying to reach. The advertiser may also use information regarding your use of the Website and/or app, such as the number of times you viewed an ad (but not any personally identifiable information), to determine which ads to deliver to you.

**Legal requirements**

Notwithstanding anything to the contrary, the Website may release your personal information to third parties: (a) in order to comply with any applicable law, regulation, search warrant or court order; or (b) in special cases, when we believe it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent or take action regarding any illegal or unauthorised activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person or violations of the Website and/or app’s Terms of Use.  If we are required or compelled to disclose your user information by a government authority, we may attempt to notify you of such disclosure if we are permitted to do so by law.

**Protecting yourself**

The Website and/or app has "Public Areas" where users can post personal content. When you disclose personal information in Public Areas, that information can be collected and used by others in various ways, including by sending unsolicited messages. You are solely responsible for any postings you make in Public Areas on the Website, and for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you're online.

You can help to protect your information by safeguarding your Website and/or app password, using caution and discretion when posting information on Public Areas of the Website and/or app. In addition, it is important that you keep us updated with your most current contact information. To review and make changes to your profile, please visit the applicable Website and/or app settings page.

**Updating your personal information**

It is important that you keep us updated with your most current contact information. When registering and creating your Website and/or app account, you must provide accurate and complete information and ensure that this information is kept accurate and up-to-date at all times.

**Personal information that is publicly available**

Any personal information or content that you voluntarily disclose online in the Website and/or app’s Public Areas becomes publicly available and can be collected and used by others.

Your username is displayed to other users when you upload content to or send messages through the Website and/or app and other Website Members can contact you through messages and comments. Therefore, it’s advised that you do not use your email address as your username if you do not wish it to become public.

When you create an account on the Website and/or app, some information regarding your account and your account activity will be provided to other users of the Website and/or app. This may include the date you opened your account, the date you last logged in to your account, your age (if you choose to make it public) and your location.

You can also choose to add personal information that will be visible to other users on your profile page (the public facing page for your account on the site). This may include a profile picture, your name, gender or other details.

If you choose to add certain features to your profile page, these features and your activity associated with these features will be displayed to other users and may be aggregated and shared with your confirmed connections or other users. Such shared activity may include the Website’s content you add as favourites.

When you add content to Public Areas of the Website and/or app, this content can be viewed by other members. You shall grant to us the right to upload this content to Public Areas of the Website and/or app and use it elsewhere on the Website and/or app, the Website’s social media channels, the Website’s email newsletter communications and associated Realbuzz Group Ltd. products and services.

**Your choices**

You can control the information that is available to other users of the Website and/or app and your confirmed friends and group members at any time, by editing your account and the features included on your profile page. You may update or correct your personal profile information and email preferences at any time by visiting your account profile page.

**Third party personal information**

You must not disclose personally identifiable information relating to any third party on the Website and/or app unless you have their express consent to do so.

**Access to your personal information**

Your personally identifiable information will be held and used by us in accordance with this Privacy policy and UK data protection legislation. You have a right to access the personally identifiable information that is held about you. To obtain a copy of the personally identifiable information the Website holds about you please contact us.

**Your personal data rights**

If at any point you believe that the personal information we hold on you is incorrect, you want us to correct or delete that information, or you no longer want us to hold that information or contact you, you can exercise your rights under the current Data Protection laws. These rights include:

Right of access

Right to rectification

Right to erasure

Right to restriction of processing

Right to data portability

Right to object

For more information about your personal data rights please visit the Information Commissioner Office website at: [https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/data-protection-reform/overview-of-the- gdpr/individuals-rights/](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/data-protection-reform/overview-of-the-)

**Making a complaint about how your personal data is being held or processed**

If you wish to raise a complaint on how we handle your personal data, you can contact Gary Irvine by writing to 4b One City Place, Chester, Cheshire, CH1 3BQ, United Kingdom or by email on gary.irvine@therealbuzzgroup.com

If you are not satisfied with our response you can make a complaint to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO). Their Helpdesk number is 0303 123 1113.

**Privacy notice updates**

We may update this policy at any time at our sole discretion. The Website and/or app will attempt to notify you of any changes by contacting you through any email address you have provided, or by placing a notice on the Website and/or app indicating the new revision date. We encourage you to periodically check back and review this policy so that you always will know what information we collect, how we use it, and to whom we disclose it.

**How to contact us**

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy policy please contact us.
